I just found out that our ocean currents
are actually driven by the sun cuz the
sun heats the equator more than the
poles. So hot air rises in the
atmosphere and flows toward the poles
where it cools, gets more dense and
drops down. So we start to get these
conveyor belts of air. But the earth
spins. So the spinning deflects the
winds like this and they flow across the
ocean pulling the surface water with it
and the next layer and the next layer
and that paired with the spinning earth
creates this spiral effect into the
ocean driving currents up to 100 m deep.
And at the same time all that heat at
the equator evaporates pure water and
leaves it more salty which flows toward
the poles, freezes and sinks making this
natural pump and driving this conveyor
belt of currents. But what's really
inside the sun? To see that, subscribe.